Guide to the Nichols Family Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1769-1873; Series I; 6.67; (19 boxes)
  - Stanhope, Charles Stanhope, 3rd earl of, 1753-1816. AL to [John Bowyer Nichols?], Chevening, 1815 Sep 11 (Box 17)
    He cannot give the information regarding the person mentioned by J. P. Nash.
  - Stickhurst, J. Henry. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1836 Sep 29 (Box 17)
    Sends engravings.
  - Stuart, John Sobieski Stolberg, 1795?-1872. ALS to unnamed recipient, Eilean Aigus, n.d. (Box 17)
    On price negotiations for illustrations in a work of Stuart's between him, the recipient, and John Gough Nichols.
  - Summer, John H. R. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Essex, 1850 Aug 10 (Box 17)
  - Tate, James. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1831 Jan 3 (Box 18)
  - Tate, James, 1771-1843
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1832 Apr 21 (Box 18)
      Hopes that "this brief letter may be in time for insertion this month [in the Gentleman's Magazine ].
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, 1834 Apr 16 (Box 18)
  - Taylor, John, 1757-1832
    - 69 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Sun Office, Strand, [v.p.], 1823-31 (Box 18)
      Explains the circumstances preventing his visiting Nichols's father.
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Warminster, 1827 Feb 8 (Box 18)
      Taylor wishes to reply to one "Verax" who wrote the Gentleman's Magazine concerning an institution for the defense of incumbents of smaller benefices.
  - Taylor, John H. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Parliament St., 1847 Jul 15 (Box 18)
    Asks for testimonial of his competency as a surveyor. Accompanied by a copy of Nichols's recommendation.
  - Taylor, Richard. ALS to Nichols & Co., Charterhouse Square, 1848 May 20 (Box 18)
    Sends piece for insertion in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Thomas, Vaughn. ALS to Nichols & Co., Ramsgate, 1840 Sep 22 (Box 18)
    Instructions for the publication of his article.
  - Thornton, William. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Grosvenor Gate, 1829 Jun 13 (Box 18)
    Submits for publication in the Gentleman's Magazine a speech and petition to the King about strengthening the established church.
  - Tiley, Maria. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Portland Place, 1846 Nov 2, 1847 Mar 13 (Box 18)
  - Tiley, W. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Reading, 1847 Jun 1 (Box 18)
    Asks Nichols to help his son get a job.
  - Tooke, William, 1777-1863. 2 ALS to Anne Nichols, Bedford Row, 1820 May 2, 1832 Sep 14 (Box 18)
    On his contributions to Miss Nichols's manuscript collection and business with her brother John Bowyer Nichols.
  - Tournay, William. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Westham College, 1819 Mar 16 (Box 18)
    About an article on the recently deceased Bishop of Peterborough.
  - Trevelyan, Sir Charles Edward, 1807-1886. ALS to Nichols & Co., Treasury Chambers, 1852 May 24 (Box 18)
    Sends payment "on account of printing the Votes etc of the House of Commons."
  - Tuckerman, S. P. ALS to Lucy Nichols, Windsor, 1853 Apr 25 (Box 18)
    Gladly accepts the kind offer to use the tickets for the Philharmonic Concert.
  - Upham, Edward, 1776-1834
    - ALS to John Nichols, Kensington, [n.y.] Nov 9 (Box 18)
      Orders subscriptions and comments on contemporary literary subjects.
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., Exeter, 1816 Mar 12 (Box 18)
      Requests further copies of books damaged by shipping.
  - Upham, John. ALS to Nichols & Co., Bath, 1818 Oct 21 (Box 18)
  - Urban, Sylvanus, pseud. ALS to unknown recipient, Strand, 1864 Jan 13 (Box 18)
    - A reminder that he has not yet received his copy of the proceedings of the Archaeological Institute. (Box 18)
  - Valpy, Richard, 1754-1836. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Sep 15 (Box 18)
    Asks if he can make alterations for the second edition of his sermons.
  - Walcott, Mackenzie Edward Charles, 1821-1880. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Westminster, n.d. (Box 18)
    Informs Nichols that he will be unable to attend the meeting of the Archaeological Institute.
  - Ward, John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Burslem, 1832 Apr 14 (Box 18)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine concerning Pliny.
  - Warner, Richard, 1763-1857. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Vicar's Mill near Lymington, n.d. (Box 18)
    Asks for assistance for his History of Hampshire.
  - Waterfield, Richard. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Thurcaston Rectory, 1847 Mar 9 (Box 18)
  - Watson, Christopher Knight, 1825-1901. Letter to John Gough Nichols, Somerset House, London, 1864 May 30 (Box 18)
    Informs Nichols of the election night for the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Whitaker, Thomas Dunham, 1759-1821. ALS to Nichols & Son, Heysham Rectory, 1817 Oct 4 (Box 18)
  - Wilkes, Miss. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Grosvenor Square, 1801 Aug 12 (Box 18)
    Arranges meeting.
  - Wilson, D. ALS to John Nichols, Glasgow, 1789 Apr 16 (Box 18)
    About the book business.
  - Wilton, Edward. ALS to John Gough Nichols, West Lavington, 1863 Apr 28 (Box 18)
    Traces the genealogies of several families and discusses some of his region's churches.
  - Wolferstan, E. P. ALS to Nichols & Co., Hatford, 1824 Mar 5 (Box 18)
    Asks them to cancel the first leaf of his poem and to reprint it with "its" for "it" in line two.
  - Wright, Thomas, 1810-1877. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Brompton, n.d. (Box 18)
    Conclusion of his article for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Young, Sir Charles George, 1795-1869
    - 4 ALS to [John Gough Nichols], College of Arms, 1835 Oct 2 (Box 18)
      About prints, pedigrees and friends.
    - 7 ALS to John Gough Nichols, ca. 1829-35 (Box 18)
      Various corrections and additions to his work on heraldry.
  - Gentleman's Magazine proofs, research notes, etc. (Box 19)
  - Nichols & Co. printing proofs, notes, etc. (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous letters., 4 (Box 19)
  - Unsorted material. (Box 19)